Onaka wa herimasu dessert tsukete ne
Omake ja dame zenbu main dish
Everyday, nice to meet you
Everybody, you and I
Oshiete ne koisuru ABC
Go, go, school carnival
Go, go, special maji love
Yume ni mogutte tondeku hirahira
Go, go, school carnival
Go, go, sweet fall in love
Dramatic
Onetsu wo check, pure pure
Hanikami-tic barebare
Heart-matic girl-uppi
Thank god, it's over...
An earthquake?!
A robot?!
TO BE CONTINUED
Hekiru Hikawa Theater
That's
my girl,
Miss Ichijo!
You're
awesome.
(>.<)
In
commemoration
of our first
episode,
I'll do
a magic
trick.
I'm Rebecca Miyamoto, the homeroom teacher of Class 1-C!
PEN
CIL
A specter lemur's big eyes are supposedly bigger than his brain!
Come on,
Miss Ichijo,
this is
anime!
You're
ruining
it!
Here.
Ma-maho!!
Wobble
Did you know that?
And FYI, my glasses are not prescription!
Episode 2
“A Safflower
Stands Out
in Any Garden”
Be sure to watch the next episode, okay! Good night!
Hey,
Miss Ichijo,
where
are you
going?