Girl.
Animation Number 001
Left hand.
Beast.
Animation Number 001
Photo
002 - 11
Ah
Animation Number 16
Aryaryagi-san!
Mr. Aryaryagi
Animation Number 16
It's "Araragi".
Sorry, I stuttered.
Don't say people's names like Airhead Hachibei does.
I think it's cute.
And isn't it strangely appropriate?
A
Don't put
rocks on
railways,
or throw
anything
in trains.
No entry
while
the barrier
is lowered.
By the way, Araragi-san, where are you going?
Back home for a minute.
Are you going out again after that?
Yeah, to Senjougahara's.
Our midterms are coming up.
I got her to help me study.
Hey, you remember Senjougahara, don't you?
That tsundere, right?
But the two of you are doing that man-woman thing, right?
I guess.
So you say you're gonna study, but you're just gonna flirt instead, right?
A
Don't put
rocks on
railways,
or throw
anything
in trains.
No entry
while
the barrier
is lowered.
Going to see your lover right before the exams that can hold you back a year?
That's just suicidal, Araragi-san.
You're asking me whether I can graduate or not?
And don't say it's suicidal!
Well, I think it's just plain suicide.
Looks like I have to go wherever I have to in order to settle things with you!
A
Don't put
rocks on
railways,
or throw
anything
in trains.
No entry
while
the barrier
is lowered.
Go wherever you have to?
Like my breasts, or my butt?
A
Don't put
rocks on
railways,
or throw
anything
in trains.
No entry
while
the barrier
is lowered.
Araragi-san, just what are you looking for in a grade-schooler's body?
Don't trail one's coat tails!
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hey, Hachikuji.
You're-
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hey, Araragi-senpai!
What a coincidence.
A
Do not
enter.
throw
things.
Danger
I captured that scene subconsciously in my head.
muishiki no uchi ni toraeta sono keshiki wa
This is not the future
zutto machinozonde ita
I've been longing for.
mirai ja naku
Unknown to me, never before seen smile...
watashi no shiranai mita koto mo nai egao
I stood there completely frozen, as if rooted to the spot.
kugitsuke ni natta mama tachitsukushita
Both of us just act so erraticaly. Our worlds stray from each other.
tenden barabara futatsu no sekai hagureteku
Everything is just so erratic. I can't shake off these contradicting feelings.
zenzen barabara mujun shite iru omoi osaekirenaku naru
With my reckless heart
gamushara na kokoro de
Someday I will leave you behind
itsu no hi ka
anata o tobikoshite
and go on
mae e susume
Before I noticed, my blind heart
yamikumo na kodou ga
itsu no ma ni
managed to outstrip me.
watashi o oikoshite
Entwined by feelings,
karamatta kimochi
Run, run. There's only one thing I can do.
hashire hashire  itsumo dekiru koto wa hitotsu
Hurry, hurry, hurry to a place beyond here.
hayaku hayaku hayaku sono mukou e
Bakemonogatari
Suruga Monkey
Suruga Kanbaru is such a famous person that there
isn't a single person in the school who doesn't know
about her,so of course, I had heard her name many
times.
No, in Suruga Kanbaru's case...
It'd be better to call her a "star" instead of
"famous person", because it'd describe her nuance
better.
Suruga Kanbaru is the ace
of the basketball team.
As a freshman, she became a regular in no time, and with her guidance,
a girls' basketball team you'd be embarrassed even to call pathetic losers
suddenly made it to nationals.
She became surrounded with a monstrous legend,
so it's weird not to call her a star.
It is not because she is very tall.
She has a figure of an ordinary high school girl.
Moreover, she is a bit short and slim.
"Graceful" is what you say.
But Suruga Kanbaru jumps.
Last year, just once, I went with some acquaintances to a game
that Suruga Kanbaru participated, she pierced, no, crushed her
opponents' defense and easily finished her drive with a dunk
shot, just like in that shounen manga popular all over Japan.
With ease and balance,
With a slight smile of a sporty girl, as if in a very good mood,
Time and time again.
Of course, she doesn't know me.
She doesn't have any reason to.
Connection
Wrap
In the end, that's what I thought.
That's what I was sure about.
Typeface used for images: HGP mincho B
Suruga Monkey, Part One
Episode 6
Do you really think a staged coincidence like this is believable?!
A
Do not
enter.
throw
things.
Danger
Hachikuji ran away?
Ran away.
Animation number 69
A
Do not
enter.
throw
things.
Danger
What's been up with you lately?
"Do you really think a staged coincidence like this is believable", huh?
I didn't think you'd think that.
It was the perfect line for this situation.  I guess this is what they mean by "witty"!
Quick-wittedness.
Animation number 73
Animation number 74
A
Do not
enter.
throw
things.
Danger
Yeah, that's it.
To be honest, I came after you.
Yeah.  I know.
Really, you knew?!
I knew you would.
You see right through everything novices like me do.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It makes me feel awkward and embarrassed.
But honestly, I admire you.
Good grief
Animation number 84
Don't you have a club to be at?
Should you be here?
My hand's messed up right now.
So, Kanbaru.
Hand.
Animation number 90
What did you want today?
Oh, right.
Left hand.
Animation number 90
Did you read the world news section of the paper this morning?
I want to hear your perspective on the political situation in Russia.
Girl.
Animation number 93
Is this a current affairs gag?!
Body.
Animation number 95
Ah, you're more interested in India's IT industry?
Limbs.
Animation number 97
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I didn't read the paper this morning.
Oh.
Oh, by the way, Araragi-senpai.  You didn't notice anything strange today, did you?
Not really.
It was just normal.
Except you.
Animation number 103
I'm a bit stressed because exams are coming up.
I'm headed to a study group today too.
Study group?
Well, I call it that, but it's one-on-one and one-sided, so it's more like tutoring.
There's someone in my class with great grades,
so I got her to help me.
Senjougahara Hitagi.
Animation number 111
Is it Senjougahara-senpai?
How did you know?
If you're talking about someone in your class with good grades, it has to be Senjougahara-senpai.
I've heard the rumors for a while.
Well, I guess.
All right, then I'll stay out of your way.
Gonna ask you to let me go for today.
I see.
Good luck, Araragi-senpai.
Rararagi-san!
Rararagi.
Animation number 125
Hachikuji.
Don't sing my name like something from a musical.
My name's Araragi.
Sorry.  I stuttered.
No, it was intentional.
I stuttuted!
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It wasn't intentional?!
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
By the way, who was that?
An underclassman.  She's the ace of the basketball club.
I don't really know why, but to be completely blunt, she's been tailing me for the past few days.
Honestly, it seems like she's up to something.
Perhaps she's fallen for you.
Huh?  No way.
I'm not the main character in some galge.
There's no way I'd just wake up one day and be popular with the girls.
The woman in me tells me I'm right.
She might confess to you soon!
What will you do?  What will you do?!
Come on.  I don't like this trend of explaining anything and everything about my love life.
It's impossible.
And I've already captured the toughest character.
Moreover, I...
Animation number 139
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I feel like I've been described unpleasantly.
Nevertheless...
Teaching is such a hard thing to do.
Lips
Animation number 147
Breasts
Animation number 149
Longissimus muscle
Animation number 150
Why do you think I'm studying?
Because you're dumb, right?
I've never had a hard time studying in my whole life,
so I don't understand what it is you don't understand.
Really?
If I work with you on getting ready for the upcoming exams,
I think you'll be able to pass.
But just what are you thinking about doing from here on?
From here on?
A
One match can cause a fire
Beware of the fire
Your ambitions.
My ambitions?
That came out of the blue.
You're already in your second month of your senior year.
You said before you're fine as long as you graduate,
but does that mean you're getting a job as soon as you graduate?
Well...
Or will you be a freeter for a while?
Or perhaps a NEET?
Or perhaps you'll choose to enroll in a trade school?
Who are you, my mom?
Mom?  What do you mean?
I'm your lover, right?
Ambitions, huh.
That's right, I've gotta decide soon.
Senjougahara, what are you gonna do?
Go to college.  If I can get a recommendation, at least.
Oh...
But if I can, I'd like to walk the same path as you.
Well, my grades are a bit too-
Then what shall we do?
Shall we live together after graduation?
If we did that, even though our paths split, we'd have more time together than we do now.
Well, it wouldn't be that bad.
It wouldn't be that bad?
What do you mean by that?
I want to.  Please let me.
Oh.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
What kind of relationship is this?
Animation number 187
You sigh a lot, Araragi-kun.
Did you know that every time you sigh, a little bit of happiness escapes?
I've already done it a thousand times or so and let my happiness escape.
I don't care how much happiness you let escape,
but I'd prefer if you didn't sigh in front of me.
It's troublesome.
Troublesome
Animation number 191
You say some really mean things.
I'm just saying you're troublesome due to lovesickness.
Lovesickness
Animation number 193
I don't even know how to reply to that.
By the way, Araragi-kun, did you know?
I've never broken up with a man.
So I don't plan on breaking up with you.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
So neither of us know how to attract others?
A
One match can cause a fire
Hey, Senjougahara.
What?
Do you still have a stapler on you?
Now that you mention it, I haven't been carrying any lately.
A
One match can cause a fire
I'm such a silly-dilly.
Silly, huh.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Come to think of it, you were the ace of the track team in middle school, right?
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Correct.
But you don't do track anymore?
A
One match can cause a fire
Beware of the fire
Correct.
I don't have any reason to.
A
One match can cause a fire
Beware of the fire
I don't want to relive the past.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Oh, right.  Hey, Senjougahara.
Answer my question.
Animation number 222
What?
Animation number 223
Did you know Kanbaru Suruga?
Kanbaru.
Animation number 224
Oh, Kanbaru Suruga, huh?
Suruga Kanbaru.
Animation number 226
That's a nostalgic name to hear.
I see.
A
One match can cause a fire
Beware of the fire
I knew it.  An old acquaintance.
When I said I was going to a study group,
Koyomi concerned with prudence.
Animation number 228
Kanbaru thought of Senjougahara rather than Hanekawa first when I mentioned the best in the class.
Long thought.
Animation number 228
Kanbaru.
Top  of the class.
Hanekawa.
Animation number 84
Is this why?
As h** fr****, she kn** h** ****l?
Animation number 228
She was my junior in middle school.
Isn't Kanbaru still your junior?
After all, you go to the same school.
"Kanbaru"?
You refer to her like you know her well.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Just what did she do, Araragi-kun?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Araragi-kun, your wounds heal very quickly, don't they?
So I bet it'd be okay if I just took out an eyeball.
Stop it, stop it!  Not my eyeball!
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
o
A
Cramp.
Animation number 246
There's nothing guilty about it!
I didn't mean it like I knew her well!
I'm devoted to you, Senjougahara!
Flame
A
One match can cause a fire
Beware of the fire
Oh, you're saying things to make me feel good.
A
One match can cause a fire
Beware of the fire
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I may have gotten a little too enthusiastic.
Did I shock you?
You look ready to kill someone when you do that.
When I kill someone, it'll be you.
I'll make you my first victim.
I won't pick anyone but you.  I promise.
I don't want that kind of twisted love!
Isn't it nice?  Try to be understanding.
If I kill you, that means I'll be the one closest to you when you're on your deathbed.
Isn't it romantic?
No way.
If someone's going to kill me, I want it to be anyone but you.
I'd rather be killed any way than how you'd kill me.
What, you hate me that much?
If anyone else kills you, I'll kill that person.
I have to keep my promise.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Anyway, we were talking about Kanbaru.
Bonds from the past.
Animation number 264
I was the track ace and she was the basketball ace.
So even though we were in different grades, we were drawn together.
And...
And...?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Even outside of team activities, in private, we looked after each other.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
By the way, Araragi-kun.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Why don't you tell me why you even mentioned her name?
If there's anything to feel guilty about, I'm sure you'll be able to explain.
Flame
Time skip.
Animation number 275
I see.
Hey, Araragi-kun.
What?
What's flooded above and on fire below?
Above is water,
below is great fire.
Animation number 278
A bath heater, right?
Bzzzt.  The answer is...
Kanbaru Suruga's household.
What are you planning on doing to the school star's house?!
Well, enough joking around.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Araragi-kun, Kanbaru realized my secret a year before you did.
Really?
It was right when I became a junior.
Meaning it was right when Kanbaru came to Naoetsu High.
Given her personality, she must have tried to help you.
Correct.
Even though I turned her down.
I dealt with it like I did when you offered.
Animation Number 292
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In spite of that, you tried to get involved.
Kanbaru didn't come back after that.
That's as far as that got.
But weren't you friends?
In middle school, yes.  Not now.
She's a total stranger.
Complete stranger.
Animation number 288
Well, I understand your relationship with Kanbaru,
but why's she following me around?
She probably found out that you were my lover.
What?
So she's interested in what kind of guy could win over Senjougahara Hitagi
and decided to check me out?
I think that's it.
Tamikurasou
She must be annoying you, Araragi-kun.
Oh well, I can't offer an explanation.
Even though it's my fault for not being able to settle my accounts with people.
But didn't you fiercely turn her down a year ago?
And it's been like that since then?
But now she's interested just because you got a boyfriend?
Tamikurasou
This is just me talking,
but for Kanbaru, Senjougahara Hitagi was her upperclassman crush.
Thus, when I refused her help,
even though she was going to listen to me and not cause any more trouble...
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
She still hasn't been able to forget about me.
Don't call her annoying.
Animation number 301
You don't have to call it annoying.
It's not like she means any harm by it.
It's annoying, whether she means harm or not.
She is annoying.
Animation number 301
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hanekawa speaking.  Sorry to keep you waiting.
He...o
What's wrong?
You don't call me that often, Araragi-kun.
Nothing important, I.......wanted to ask
......something........it okay, Hanekawa?
No, it's fine.
I was just doing some light studying.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Weren'....... and Senjougahara stu..........
...same m..dle school?
That's right.
Don't you ha..................know
an underclassman ca......... Suruga Kanbaru?
Of course I know about that.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Really?
I hea.. .... ...Kanbaru and
Senjougahara were ........ .......
in middle school?
The "Baruhara Combo".
Valhalla Combination.
Animation number 325
They were called the "Baruhara Combo".
Senjougahara-san from the track team, and Kanbaru-san from the basketball team.  The "Baruhara Combo".
"Baruhara Combo"?
What do you mean, "Baruhara"?
The baru from Kanbaru and the hara from Senjougahara make Baruhara.
And "Valhalla" is the heavenly palace of the chief god in Norse mythology, Odin.
So it means the holy place of the god of battle, whence to the spirits of heroes who fell in battle were invited.
That works with the "god" in Kanbaru's name and the "battlefield" in Senjougahara's name, huh.
Thus, "Baruhara Combo".
That's a pretty clever way of putting it.
Well, they called them a combo, so at least it wasn't like they didn't get along or were on bad terms.
I see.
And Senjougahara-san stayed on the team right up until graduation,
so they must have at least known each other as athletes.
You know everything.
I don't know everything, just what I know.
Say, Hanekawa, I.........middle school
Senjougahara was nothing ..........
......popular with juniors, right?
Oh, yeah.  She was popular among both boys and girls.
She had a good reputation among upperclassmen and people of her grade,
but I guess she was most popular among younger girls.
That's what you asked me about, and that's how it was.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
But you're not interested in how Senjougahara-san used to be,
you're interested in her now, right?
Ah.
It's great that you like each other, but try to keep
proper male-female relations in mind, Araragi-kun.
Senjougahara-san seems serious,
so I don't think you can let this become a
relationship where you're always irritated at each other.
Senjougahara-san is difficult.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
So because of that, well...  I don't want to talk like I really know all that well,
but Senjougahara has built an
impregnable self field around herself.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Just like the one you have.
Everyone has a self field they call "privacy" or whatever,
but for you and her, it goes beyond that and turns into a siege mentality.
And for people like you, just interacting with other people is often unpleasant.
Am I right?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
About both of you?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
But think of it this way, Araragi-kun.
Even if you're not social, that's
different from being misanthropic.
Receiving guests is the most difficult thing for me, but not if you're the guest.
I'm bothered by the very fact that people exist,
but you're an exception.
Animation number 351
You get what it means, right?
And you understand what I want to say?
...k you. S..ry for ...... ..ur time
... ...ing you ans... ...pid que.....ons.
No, I get it.
Wanting to know about your dear girlfriend is normal.
But it's best not to peer too deep into a lover's past.
It won't be all fun and games,
so try not to dig too deep too quick.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
All right, bye-bye.
If I could, I'd like to give Senjougahara back what she lost and what she threw away.
If I can, I'd like to bring back what she has lost,
what she threw away.
Animation number 360
It might be none of my business, and an unwanted gift.
But I can't help thinking about it.
But I can't stop thinking about it.
Animation number 363
After all, there's no way I could do it.
Could you give this to Oshino-san?
Reminiscence
Animation number 367
What's this-?
Payment for Oshino?
You got it ready quicker than I thought.
Did you work part-time?
I helped my dad out with his work for a little bit.
Well, I guess it's more like, "I overdid helping him", but that's the money I earned doing it.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I was gonna hand it over, but I forgot it at her place.
No doubt.
Animation number 32
This is a monster.
Animation number 383
Why does this monster
attack me?
Animation number 391
ga
u
Animation number 392
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Black Scene
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Araragi-kun.
Hey, long time no see.
I came to bring the thing you forgot.
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part One
CONTINUED NEXT TIME
are ga denebu arutairu bega
That's Deneb, Altair, Vega
kimi wa yubisasu natsu no daisankaku
the Summer Triangle that you pointed out.
覚
え
て
oboete
I remember that
空
を
見
る
sora o miru
and look at the sky.
yatto mitsuketa orihime-sama
There's Orihime, I've found her at last
dakedo doko darou hikoboshi-sama
But where is Hikoboshi, I wonder?
kore ja hitoribocchi
It's lonely like that.
makkura na sekai kara miageta
We looked up from the pitch-dark world,
yozora wa hoshi ga furu you de
and the stars in the night sky were ready to fall.
itsu kara darou
I wonder when it was,
kimi no koto o
that I started chasing
oikakeru watashi ga ita
after you.
douka onegai
Please, if possible,
odorokanaide
don't be surprised
聞
い
て
よ
kiite yo
understand them.
私
の
watashi no
These feelings
kono omoi o
of mine.
This isn't Karen!
And this isn't Tsukihi!
Then who are we?
Dejikarubi is not digital?
Dejikarubi is some sort of meat dish
"A Pebble by the Wayside" is not a robot?
"A Pebble by the Wayside" (Robou no ishi) is a book by Yuzu Yamamoto.
First in ranking, but not a king?
Overhaul is not a hole?
"Haul" part is written as "Hooru", just like "Hole".
Schedule is not a calorific value?
Schedule = Sukejuuru, ends with Juuru which is japanese for Joule, unit of energy.
Elocution is not erotic?
Isn't undeserved honor the same as a mini honor?
Undeserved honor is written as "mi ni amaru kouei".
Isn't receiving a favor the same as being deeply loved?
A favor (chouai) sounds similar to a deep love (chou ai).
It isn't, right?
Of course, it isn't!
Preview quiz!
Quiz!
This isn't one!
This isn't?!
Next time: Suruga monkey, part two.
Preview
Next Time
Suruga Monkey, Part Two
If it isn't a preview quiz, what's this?
Not a quiz.